JOHNNASTHERN BACA-HERNANDEZ

157 Goethe, San Francisco, CA 94112 (415) 610-6393 - bacahernandezj@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Customer-oriented Retail Manager with over 5 years of experience in building relationships, developing marketing campaigns, cultivating partnerships, retaining top accounts and growing profit channels. Knowledgeable in Microsoft Excel and Word. Tactical team builder with expertise in introducing products, implementing pricing models and determining customer needs to deliver effective solutions.

SKILLS

- Sales and marketing
- Verbal and written communication
- Customer service
- Data collection and analysis
- Equipment inspection and testing
- Maintenance procedures
- Data entry background

- Microsoft Word expertise
- Types 50 Words Per Minute
- POS systems knowledge
- Goal-oriented
- Computer literate
- Money handling abilities
- Fluent in Spanish

WORK HISTORY

04/2019 to Current

Autonomous Driving Trainer

Cruise Automation Inc. – San Francisco, CA

- Organized and submitted company forms and regulatory documents
- Conducted on-the-job training classes and demonstrated principles, techniques, procedures and methods of diverse subjects
- Created appropriate learning environments for drivers
- Evaluated 30+ trainees' performance and issued progress reports

08/2018 to 07/2019

Manager Of Tire Sales

Bridgestone Retail Operations LLC. – San Rafael, CA

- Inspected and tested equipment to locate worn and damaged parts
- Ordered repair parts and ensured requests for parts were executed in timely manner
- Performed diagnostic and troubleshooting procedures to find and identify root
- Supervised and directed crew of 7 employees in tracking of tire fatigue, pressure, tread depths and sidewall inspections on automotive equipment
- Performed tire rotations, mounts and balancing on all types of vehicles

03/2018 to 07/2018 Lead Teller Operations Specialist

WEST AMERICA BANK – SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA

- Perform clerical tasks such as typing, filing, and microfilm photography
- Compose, type, and mail customer statements and other correspondence related to issues such as discrepancies and outstanding unpaid items
- Monitor bank vaults to ensure cash balances are correct

- Obtain and process information required for the provision of services, such as opening accounts, savings plans, and purchasing bonds
- Explain, promote, or sell products or services such as travelers' checks, savings bonds, money orders, and cashier's checks, using computerized information about customers to tailor recommendations
- Resolve problems or discrepancies concerning customers' accounts
- Counted as much as \$100k in daily funds with manual and machine-assisted methods

10/2015 to 02/2018 Teller

CHASE BANK – SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA

- Cash checks and pay out money after verifying that signatures are correct, that written and numerical amounts agree, and that accounts have sufficient funds
- Receive checks and cash for deposit, verify amounts, and check accuracy of deposit slips
- Enter customers' transactions into computers to record transactions and issue computer-generated receipts
- Processed 3 cash withdrawals per 5 minutes accurately and efficiently

10/2013 to 01/2017

Cashier Lead

American Eagle Outfitters - San Francisco, CA

- Monitor checkout stations to ensure adequate cash available and staff appropriately
- Supervise 10+ and provide on-the-job training
- Greet 100+ customers entering establishments
- Process merchandise returns and exchanges
- Receive payment by cash, check, credit cards, vouchers, or automatic debits
- Oversaw work of 8 cashiers to identify strengths and weaknesses in customer service, payment processing or merchandising plans and maximize performance
- Inventoried stock and placed new orders to keep supplies within optimal levels for expected demands
- Maximized customer satisfaction by assisting customers complete purchases, locate items and sign up for rewards programs
- Inspected checkout areas every 15 minutes and directed team members in cleaning, trash removal and other actions to restore professional appearances

EDUCATION

Expected in 2021

High School Diploma: Business Administration And Management SKYLINE COLLEGE - SAN BRUNO, CALIFORNIA

High School Diploma
MISSION HIGH - San Francisco, CA